Dian Adriansyah

Applications Developer

Experience to be collecting and transform the requirement into solution design. Lead the planning of product release plans and set the expectation for delivery of new functionalities, manage team, help identify and remove impediments, and resolve conflicts. ability to develop and detailed plan in software development. Develop Apps with SCRUM methodology to drive agile project management,

WORK EXPERIENCE

IT Business Analyst

Maret 2018 - April 2022

PT Mitra Integrasi Informatika project Professional Service site PT Jasamarga Jakarta

- Understand and translate business needs into requirement artifacts, collaborate with teams to develop comprehensive IT solutions and prioritize according to business value.
- Working with SCRUM make the product backlogs, facilitate daily scrum, sprint
 planning, sprint demo, and retrospective meetings to monitor and evaluate the
 effectiveness of implemented solutions and recommend enhancements or
 modifications as needed.
- Collaborate with stakeholders to understand and document business requirement and analyze existing business processes to recommend improvements.
- Lead the planning of product release plans and set the expectation for delivery
 of new functionalities, manage team, help identify and remove impediments,
 and resolve conflicts.
- Manage project documentation(BRD, FSD/FRS, Process Flow Diagrams,
 System Design, User Guide), including status reports, timelines, and budgets.

Product Owner

PT Mitra Integrasi Informatika project Professional Service site PT Jasamarga Jakarta

- Gather requirements and prioritize them based on business value or user needs and break down requirements into user stories with detailed acceptance criteria to guide development efforts.
- Working with SCRUM make the product backlogs, facilitate daily scrum, sprint planning, sprint demo, and retrospective meetings.
- Collaborate with development teams to ensure a shared understanding of requirements and provide clarifications as needed during implementation,
- Lead the planning of product release plans and set the expectation for delivery of new functionalities, manage team, help identify and remove impediments, and resolve conflicts.

Front End Developer

Mai 2022 - Present

PT Mitra Integrasi Informatika project Aplikasi Unit Kerja on site PT Jasamarga, Jakarta

- Working with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, to create user interface from hi-fi mockup become responsive web.
- Using versioning GIT to Collaborate with back-end developer and integrated from back-end developer with Rest API
- Collaborate with the development team to design, implement, and maintain the user interface and user experience of web applications.
- Working with SCRUM team methodology to develop applications.

ORGANISATION EXPERIENCE

- KMTI UMY (Keluarga Mahasiswa Teknologi Informasi) as Head of Public Relation Division 2014 - 2016
- BEM FT UMY (Badan Eksekutif Mahasiswa Fakultas Teknik) Division Kastrad (Kajian dan Strategi) as Member 2015 2016
- KMPK LS Yogyakarta (Keluarga Mahasiswa Kalianda Lampung Selatan) Head of division PSDM (Pengembangan Sumber Daya Mahasiswa) 2015-2017
- AERIAL TEAM TI UMY (Drone Club Study) Pilot DJI Phantom 3, 2015 2017



CONTACT

- driansyahsaputra@gmail.com
- +62821-3547-5864
- github.com/driansyahsaputra
- https://drianportfolio.netlify.app

SKILLS

Technology:

- SDLC (SCRUM)
- Balsamiq Mockup
- Visual Studio Code
- Figma
- Visio
- Jira
- Miro
- GitHub
- Postman
- Consume Rest API

Tools and Programming:

- HTML
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- Laravel
- jQuery
- Ajax
- Flutter
- ReactMySQL
- Postgres.

EDUCATION

Universitas Muhammadiyah Yogyakarta - Information Technology 2013-2017

TRAINING

- SCRUM by Duta Academy 2018
- UI Design Mobil and Mobile by Rubrik Grafi, 2021
- Software Engineering by NIIT Academic, 2015 - 2018